const ques= [
{
'question':'Who invented Java Programming?',
'a':'steve jobs',
'b':'james gosling',
'c':'dennis ritchei',
'd':'rasmus lerdorf',
'correct':'b'
},

{
'question':'Which statement is true about Java?',
'a':'Java is a sequence-dependent programming language',
'b':'Java is a code dependent programming language',
'c':'Java is a platform-dependent programming language',
'd':'Java is a platform-independent programming language',
'correct':'d'
}
,
{
'question':'Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?',
'a':'JRE',
'b':'JDK',
'c':'JIT',
'd':'JVM',
'correct':'b'
},
{
'question':'Which one of the following is not a Java feature?',
'a':'Object-oriented',
'b':'Use of pointers',
'c':' Portable',
'd':'Dynamic and Extensible',
'correct':'b'
},
{
'question':'Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?',
'a':'identifier & keyword', 
'b':'identifier',
'c':' keyword',
'd':'none of the mentioned',
'correct':'d'
},
{
'question':'What is the extension of java code files?',
'a':'.java',
'b':'.js',
'c':'.class',
'd':'.txt',
'correct':'a'
},
{
'question':'Which environment variable is used to set the java path?',
'a':'MAVEN_Path',
'b':'JavaPATH',
'c':'JAVA',
'd':'JAVA_HOME',
'correct':'d'
},
{
'question':'Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?',
'a':'Polymorphism',
'b':'Encapsulation',
'c':'Compilation',
'd':'Inheritance',
'correct':'c'
},
{
'question':'Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?',
'a':'Multiple polymorphism',
'b':'Compile time polymorphism',
'c':' Multilevel polymorphism',
'd':'Execution time polymorphism',
'correct':'b'
},
   {
'question':'What is Truncation in Java?',
'a':'Floating-point value assigned to a Floating type',
'b':'Floating-point value assigned to an integer type',
'c':'Integer value assigned to floating type',
'd':'Integer value assigned to floating type',
'correct':'b'
   }, 
]

